A Guide to the Connecticut Milk Producers Association Records 1979.0004
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Connecticut Milk Producers Association Records
1919-1947
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1979.0004
45 Linear Feet
Based in Hartford, Connecticut, the Connecticut Milk Producers Association was a professional organization for the milk producers of Connecticut. It provided its members with a monthly newsletter and kept track of prices and production of milk within the state as well as in the neighboring states.
History
Based in Hartford, Connecticut, the Connecticut Milk Producers Association was a professional organization for the milk producers of Connecticut>. It provided its members with a monthly newsletter and kept track of prices and production of milk within the state as well as in the neighboring states.
Scope and Content
The collection contains ledgers that document the quantity of milk purchased in Connecticut from 1922 through 1937. It appears that each member milk producer kept his own ledgers, which were then bound together by the CMPA with those of other members. The ledgers record patron names, amounts of milk specified and produced, and cost and payment for each milk producer. Each volume covers a six month period and is arranged alphabetically by name of milk producer. The Bulletin was issued monthly and is bound chronologically.
Custodial History
The Record of Milk Purchased ledgers were acquired for the University of Connecticut by Professor E. A. Perregaux in the late 1940s or early 1950s. They were stored in the Wilbur Cross Library until 1979, when they were transferred to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the University Libraries.
Acquisition Information
The Bulletins were originally sent from the Connecticut Milk Producers Association to the Economic Service of Connecticut State College(now University of Connecticut). The Library collected the Bulletins and bound them into five volumes. They were moved to the Archives in 1993 to become part of the CMPA collection. The correspondence and records of the association auditor and accountant, Irving Goldblatt, were donated in April 2011 by his family.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
New England (general region); Dairy products industry; Financial Records; Publications (documents); Milk yield; Milk trade; Dairying; Connecticut (state)
- Series I: Record of Milk Purchased Ledgers, 1922-1937
  - 1922 April - 1923 March (Box 1)
  - 1923 April - 1923 September (Box 2)
  - 1923 October - 1924 March (Box 3)
  - 1924 April - 1924 September (Box 4)
  - 1924 October - 1925 March (Box 5)
  - 1925 April - September (Box 6)
  - 1925 October - 1926 March (Box 7)
  - 1926 April - September (Box 8)
  - 1926 October - 1927 March (Box 9)
  - 1927 April - September (Box 10)
  - 1927 October - 1928 March (Box 11)
  - 1928 April - September (Box 12)
  - 1928 October - 1929 March (Box 13)
  - 1929 April - September (Box 14)
  - 1929 October - 1930 March (Box 15)
  - 1930 April - September (Box 16)
  - 1930 October - 1931 March (Box 17)
  - 1931 April - September (Box 18)
  - 1931 October - 1932 March (Box 19)
  - 1932 April - September (Box 20)
  - 1932 October - 1933 March (Box 21)
  - 1933 April - September (Box 22)
  - (bound), 1933 October - 1934 March (Box 23)
  - 1934 April - September (Box 24)
  - 1934 October - 1935 March (Box 25)
  - (bound), 1935 April - September (Box 26)
  - 1935 October - 1936 March (Box 27)
  - (bound), 1936 October - 1937 March (Box 28)
- Series II: Bulletin, 1919-1947
  - v. I, Nos. 1 - 72, 1919 August - 1925 July (Box 29)
  - v. II, Nos. 73 - 173, 1925 August - 1933 December (Box 29)
  - v. III, Nos. 174 - 256, 1934 January - 1940 December (Box 29)
  - v. IV, Nos. 257 - 304, 1941 January - 1944 December (Box 29)
  - v. V, Nos. 305 - 340, 1945 January - 1947 December (Box 29)
- Series III: Correspondence and financial records, 1935-1936
  - Correspondence and financial records of of Irving Goldblatt, auditor/accountant for the association, 1935-1936 (Box 30)